<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>hugo on Guilherme Pedrosa</title>
    <link>https://gtpedrosa.github.io/tags/hugo/</link>
    <description>Recent content in hugo on Guilherme Pedrosa</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Dec 2021 09:11:00 -0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://gtpedrosa.github.io/tags/hugo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrating CI tool from travis to circleci for hugo blog on ghpages</title>
      <link>https://gtpedrosa.github.io/blog/migrating-ci-tool-from-travis-to-circleci-for-hugo-blog-on-ghpages/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Dec 2021 09:11:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gtpedrosa.github.io/blog/migrating-ci-tool-from-travis-to-circleci-for-hugo-blog-on-ghpages/</guid>
      <description>When Travis CI was acquired by Idera, it didn&amp;rsquo;t take long to cease its support for open source projects. This affected this blog since I overengineered it to learn some dev-ops skills. As result, I was forced to migrate the continuous integration (CI) tool from Travis to CircleCI. While I was at it, I took advantage and included a docker image for the build instead of declaring the dependencies installation as part of the CI build.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrading an outdated Hugo template</title>
      <link>https://gtpedrosa.github.io/blog/upgrading-an-outdated-hugo-template/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2020 18:04:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gtpedrosa.github.io/blog/upgrading-an-outdated-hugo-template/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I wanted to restart blogging in a new machine. After installing the latest hugo version at the time and pulling my git repo I soon realized:
 Hugo version in which the blog was built was v0.31, whereas the current one was v0.68.1. The cocoa development was abandonned and no updates were made to cope with hugo enhancements  Since I do like this theme and already had a fork of it I decided to try and upgrade it by myself, even though I have no experience with the go programming language or web development.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>