<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Guilherme Pedrosa</title>
    <link>https://gtpedrosa.github.io/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Guilherme Pedrosa</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2015 06:42:21 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://gtpedrosa.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving files on windows with python: shutil alternative</title>
      <link>https://gtpedrosa.github.io/blog/moving-files-on-windows-with-python-shutil-alternative/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 11:20:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gtpedrosa.github.io/blog/moving-files-on-windows-with-python-shutil-alternative/</guid>
      <description>Transfering data from my HD across a network, I have hit a bottleneck: the file transfer speed was dramatically slow. In fact, the transfer took more time to finish than it took to generate the files. It was an unnaceptable situation due HD constraints.
It turns out that the file being copied to another partition is virtually chunked, and each of them copied sequentialy. The more chunks the slower the transfer is, while larger chunks increase memory usage [1]​.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrading an outdated Hugo template</title>
      <link>https://gtpedrosa.github.io/blog/upgrading-an-outdated-hugo-template/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2020 18:04:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gtpedrosa.github.io/blog/upgrading-an-outdated-hugo-template/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I wanted to restart blogging in a new machine. After installing the latest hugo version at the time and pulling my git repo I soon realized:
 Hugo version in which the blog was built was v0.31, whereas the current one was v0.68.1. The cocoa development was abandonned and no updates were made to cope with hugo enhancements  Since I do like this theme and already had a fork of it I decided to try and upgrade it by myself, even though I have no experience with the go programming language or web development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading SQL Dumps with SQL Server management Studio</title>
      <link>https://gtpedrosa.github.io/blog/reading-sql-dumps-with-sql-server-management-studio/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2020 10:58:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gtpedrosa.github.io/blog/reading-sql-dumps-with-sql-server-management-studio/</guid>
      <description>This post is about how to inspect the content of SQL database (.mdf and .ldf files). The answer is to attach these files to an existing SQL server instance, instead of opening them directly with a tool such as SQL Management Studio. This was not clear time until I stumbled upon this video.
Steps  Keep a SQL Server instance running in the background; Fire up SQL Management studio and connect to this instance by providing .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Emacs from source</title>
      <link>https://gtpedrosa.github.io/blog/building-emacs-from-source/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2020 10:59:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gtpedrosa.github.io/blog/building-emacs-from-source/</guid>
      <description>Steps needed to install emacs locally, mantaining pre-existing installation intact. In the end you will two different versions of emacs running in your system.
 Install dependencies:  sudo apt-get install autoconf automake libtool texinfo build-essential xorg-dev libgtk-3-dev libjpeg-dev libncurses5-dev libdbus-1-dev libgif-dev libtiff-dev libm17n-dev libpng-dev librsvg2-dev libotf-dev libgnutls28-dev libxml2-dev libxpm-dev  Download emacs from a nearby mirror Extract downloaded file. In this case it is emacs-26.3.tar.xz, and go to the extracted folder:  cd ~/Downloads tar -xf emacs-26.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using SQLAlchemy to navigate an existing database</title>
      <link>https://gtpedrosa.github.io/blog/using-sqlalchemy-to-navigate-an-existing-database/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2019 18:56:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gtpedrosa.github.io/blog/using-sqlalchemy-to-navigate-an-existing-database/</guid>
      <description>Given the task to interact with an existing database I felt compelled to use the ORM abstraction instead of making queries with raw sql. My aim was to avoid the common pitfalls regarding making text templates for sqlqueries, prone to sql injection exploits, and enhance query composability.
I&amp;rsquo;ve found there are essentialy two ways to approach this task: through reflextion or a declarative model. Both approaches are explained in the following sections.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using httr with JSON API&#39;s</title>
      <link>https://gtpedrosa.github.io/blog/using-httr-with-json-apis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2019 11:35:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gtpedrosa.github.io/blog/using-httr-with-json-apis/</guid>
      <description>It is incredbly easy to make R interact with external API&amp;rsquo;s. I&amp;rsquo;ve found the httr vignette to be a great resource on how to make a wrapper to interact with them. However I&amp;rsquo;ve stumbled in one quirk that is worth mentioning.
While creating a body to a POST request message, encoded with json, I verified that my requests were being turned down by the server. The issue was related to a behavior of the jsonlite package, one of httr&amp;rsquo;s dependencies which uses auto_unbox=TRUE by default.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generating documentation of Matlab scripts automatically with mkdocs</title>
      <link>https://gtpedrosa.github.io/blog/generating-documentation-of-matlab-scripts-automatically-with-mkdocs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2019 23:06:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gtpedrosa.github.io/blog/generating-documentation-of-matlab-scripts-automatically-with-mkdocs/</guid>
      <description>Something that always called my attention is how much more documented and even appealing to newcomers projects in python or R are if compared to Matlab in general. One exception is MatConvNet, a library that implements convolutional neural networks (CNNs) in Matlab and has a good looking and helpful documentation.
The documentation stands out as it is produced with MkDocs, a static site generator based on markdown specific for project documentation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using org mode and ox-hugo to replace markdown in hugo workflow</title>
      <link>https://gtpedrosa.github.io/blog/using-org-mode-and-ox-hugo-to-replace-markdown-in-hugo-workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2019 13:41:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gtpedrosa.github.io/blog/using-org-mode-and-ox-hugo-to-replace-markdown-in-hugo-workflow/</guid>
      <description>I have decided to give org mode blogging a go. Why org mode? The main reasons for this were:
 Abandon markdown: I always get confused by markdown markup choices. I find myself constantly reaching for markdown cheatsheet to find out how to insert a link. &amp;ldquo;Is it parenthesis or brackets?&amp;rdquo; gets me every time; Increase familiarity with org mode synthax to use it in my literary programming workflows in the near future (tangle+babel); Reduce friction to create new blog posts using the great ox-hugo by Kaushal Modi.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exchanging data between Matlab/Octave and R</title>
      <link>https://gtpedrosa.github.io/blog/exchanging-data-between-matlab/octave-and-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2018 13:14:46 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gtpedrosa.github.io/blog/exchanging-data-between-matlab/octave-and-r/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve had the need to read &lt;em&gt;uff&lt;/em&gt; files into R. This file format was developped at the University of Cincinnati to standardize the way vibration measurements are stored. It so happens there isn&amp;rsquo;t a library capable of importing &lt;em&gt;uff&lt;/em&gt; files into R, but there is one written in python and another for Matlab.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apresentando o Docear</title>
      <link>https://gtpedrosa.github.io/blog/apresentando-o-docear/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2017 06:42:38 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gtpedrosa.github.io/blog/apresentando-o-docear/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Já ouviu falar no software Docear? Eu também não havia até o início do mestrado, então deixe-me apresenta-los a este fantástico software.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>editor vs processador</title>
      <link>https://gtpedrosa.github.io/blog/editor-vs-processador/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2017 17:58:45 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gtpedrosa.github.io/blog/editor-vs-processador/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Com o objetivo de redigir textos científicos, qual a ferramenta mais adequada para o trabalho? Editores ou processadores de texto?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gerenciador de referências bibliográficas: Jabref</title>
      <link>https://gtpedrosa.github.io/blog/gerenciador-de-refer%C3%AAncias-bibliogr%C3%A1ficas-jabref/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2017 19:55:02 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gtpedrosa.github.io/blog/gerenciador-de-refer%C3%AAncias-bibliogr%C3%A1ficas-jabref/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Este post tem como único objetivo explicar porque escolhi utilizar o &lt;strong&gt;Jabref&lt;/strong&gt; para gerenciar minhas referências.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Programação Literária</title>
      <link>https://gtpedrosa.github.io/blog/programa%C3%A7%C3%A3o-liter%C3%A1ria/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2017 19:11:44 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gtpedrosa.github.io/blog/programa%C3%A7%C3%A3o-liter%C3%A1ria/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Este conceito foi criado por ninguém menos que Donald Knuth (lembra-se do \( \LaTeX \)?). Knuth argumenta que os programas de computador devem ser tão legíveis quanto obras literárias.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organizando a casa - A estrutura de diretórios</title>
      <link>https://gtpedrosa.github.io/blog/organizando-a-casa-a-estrutura-de-diret%C3%B3rios/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2017 19:11:44 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gtpedrosa.github.io/blog/organizando-a-casa-a-estrutura-de-diret%C3%B3rios/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Antes de inciar o desenvolvimento do meu mestrado me deparei com o seguinte dilema: como organizar o diretório principal? Existe uma maneira ótima e/ou recomendada para organizar os arquivos?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ferramentas e métodos de organização aplicados ao mestrado</title>
      <link>https://gtpedrosa.github.io/blog/ferramentas-e-m%C3%A9todos-de-organiza%C3%A7%C3%A3o-aplicados-ao-mestrado/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2016 19:11:44 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gtpedrosa.github.io/blog/ferramentas-e-m%C3%A9todos-de-organiza%C3%A7%C3%A3o-aplicados-ao-mestrado/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Desejo compartilhar através de uma série de posts o processo utilizado na elaboração de minha dissertação de mestrado. O objetivo é apresentar temas, softwares e processos que topei durante esta jornada. Os posts estão divididos nos seguintes temas:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing a virtualenv with specific python version</title>
      <link>https://gtpedrosa.github.io/blog/installing-a-virtualenv-with-specific-python-version/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2016 19:11:44 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gtpedrosa.github.io/blog/installing-a-virtualenv-with-specific-python-version/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When trying to install the requirements for a course on coursera I found out that my system&amp;rsquo;s python distribution was a bit outdated. Since I did not want to change anything systemwide (and possibily break things) I decided to finally go for a virtual environment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>